Register of the Ivy and Tatiana Litvinov papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ivy and Tatiana Litvinov papers
1890-2008
87075
Hoover Institution Archives
53 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 1 oversize box (23.8 linear feet)
The Ivy and Tatiana Litvinov papers contain autobiographical, fictional, and other writings; interview transcripts; diaries; correspondence; and sound recordings relating to the life of Ivy Litvinov in Great Britain and the Soviet Union, her marriage to the Soviet foreign minister Maksim Litvinov, and British and Russian literature. The papers also include correspondence, speeches and writings, and art works by Ivy Litvinov's daughter, Tatiana Litvinov, who was an artist and translator.
Litvinov, Ivy.
Litvinov, Tatiana.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987, with an increment received in 2016.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Ivy Litvinov (1889-1977) was a British-Russian writer and translator, and the wife of prominent Soviet diplomat Maxim Litvinov, who served as People's Commissar for Foreign Affairs and as ambassador to the United States. The couple survived political turmoil and Stalin's purges. Ivy accompanied her husband on some of his diplomatic postings but lived mainly in the USSR for most of her adult life.
Ivy wrote His Master’s Voice, a detective story (1930) later published in the USA as A Moscow Mystery, and worked on short stories she contributed to The New Yorker and other magazines beginning in the 1960s. A collection of her short stories was published in 1971 in book form as She Knew She Was Right. Ivy was also the author of numerous translations of Russian literature into English. Additionally, she wrote or edited reference books for Russian-speakers learning English.
Ivy's daughter, Tatiana Litvinov (1918-1997), was a bilingual translator from Russian into English and from English into Russian, and a remarkable graphic artist.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Ivy and Tatiana Litvinov papers include correspondence; diaries; annotations; literary reviews; autobiographical, fictional, and other writings; photographs; sound recordings; and art works of Ivy and Tatiana Litvinov and other family members. The materials relate to the life of Ivy Litvinov in Great Britain and the Soviet Union, her marriage to the Soviet foreign minister Maksim Maksimovich Litvinov, and British and Russian literature. Of particular interest is correspondence by Maksim Litvinov to Ivy and Tatiana.
The collection consists of two parts acquired at different times; each part is organized into files by the individual's name.
Litvinov, M. M. (Maksim Maksimovich), 1876-1951.; British literature.; Russian literature.; Soviet Union--Social conditions.
- Ivy Litvinov File [part I], 1909-1988 (Boxes 1-10)
  - Diaries, 1973 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1909-1980
    - Draft and fragments, 1950-1975 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - Unidentified, 1946-1977 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - General, 1940-1976 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - Identified by first name, 1931-1976
      - Alix, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 5)
      - Eileen, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 6)
      - Florence, circa 1965 (Box-folder 1: 7)
      - George (Iurii), 1975 (Box-folder 1: 8)
      - Jerry, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 1: 9)
      - Lesley, 1975 (Box-folder 1: 10)
      - Lucy, 1931-1958 (Box-folder 1: 11)
      - Mary, 1974 (Box-folder 1: 12)
      - Sam, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 13)
      - Shelley, 1975 (Box-folder 1: 14)
      - Teresa, circa 1975 (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - Bell, Adrian, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Beoyl, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - Biggs, Mary, 1976 (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - Boyars, Marion, 1977 (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - Bradford, Ned, 1975 (Box-folder 1: 20)
    - Carswell, Catherine and Donald, 1926-1944
      - 1926 (Box-folder 1: 21)
      - 1927 (Box-folder 1: 22)
      - 1928 (Box-folder 1: 23)
      - 1929 (Box-folder 1: 24)
      - 1930 (Box-folder 1: 25)
      - 1931 (Box-folder 1: 26)
      - 1932 (Box-folder 1: 27)
      - 1934 (Box-folder 1: 28)
      - 1935-1936 (Box-folder 1: 29)
      - 1943-1944 (Box-folder 1: 30)
    - Carswell, Ianthe and John, 1960-1980
      - 1960-1962 (Box-folder 2: 1)
      - 1964-1966 (Box-folder 2: 2)
      - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2: 3)
      - 1970-1973 (Box-folder 2: 4)
      - 1976-1980 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - Charles Webb & Sons, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - Chukovskii, Kornei Ivanovich, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - Crankshaw, Edward, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - Daily Express, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - Dodd, N., 1976-1977 (Box-folder 2: 10)
      Scope and Contents note
      Includes a letter to Pavel Litvinov.
    - Efremov, Andrei, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - The Evening Standard, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Fischer, George, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 2: 13)
    - Fischer, Louis, 1960 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - Freidin, Gregory, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 2: 15)
    - Freud, Anna, 1977 (Box-folder 2: 16)
    - Fry, W., circa 1975 (Box-folder 2: 17)
    - Goetz, Ruth, 1974 (Box-folder 2: 18)
    - Goldberg, Anatol and Elsa, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 2: 19)
    - Good Housekeeping, circa 1970 (Box-folder 2: 20)
    - Gordon, Giles, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 2: 21)
    - Grace, Emily, 1960-1977 (Box-folder 2: 22)
    - Harari, M., 1960-1961 (Box-folder 2: 23)
    - Hayter, circa 1970 (Box-folder 2: 24)
    - Huddleston, C. Roy, 1974 (Box-folder 2: 25)
    - Hunt, Jeremy (Observer), 1974-1976 (Box-folder 2: 26)
    - Hyde, Joan, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 27)
    - Kaiser, Robert G., 1974 (Box-folder 2: 28)
    - Kemp, A., circa 1965 (Box-folder 2: 29)
    - Klyshko, Phyllis, 1945-1961 (Box-folder 2: 30)
    - Lambert, 1975 (Box-folder 2: 31)
    - Litvinov, Maksim Maksimovich, 1938-1950
      - 1938 (Box-folder 2: 32)
      - 1939 (Box-folder 2: 33)
        Includes a letter to Zina.
      - 1941 (Box-folder 2: 34)
      - 1949-1950 (Box-folder 2: 35)
    - Litvinov, Mikhail Maksimovich, 1938-1977 (Box-folder 2: 36)
    - Litvinova (nee Iasinovskaia), Flora, 1958-1977 (Box-folder 2: 37)
    - Loos, Anita, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 38)
    - Lowenfish, Lee, 1976 (Box-folder 2: 39)
    - McKensie, Rachel (New Yorker, New York), 1966-1973 (Box-folder 2: 40)
    - Meynell, Viola, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 2: 41)
      Includes two photographs of Ivy, Viola, and Christina.
    - Norman, Dorothy, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - Petrova, A. V., 1961 (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - Prashker, B., 1973 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - Rantz, Berta, 1934-1977
      - 1934 (Box-folder 3: 4)
      - 1942 (Box-folder 3: 5)
      - 1943 (Box-folder 3: 6)
      - 1972-1977 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - Schechler, Leona, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - Secker, Martin, 1971 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Seddon, Nell, 1971-1977
      - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 3: 10)
      - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 3: 11)
      - 1975 (Box-folder 3: 12)
      - 1976-1977 (Box-folder 3: 13)
    - Slavic Review, circa 1965 (Box-folder 3: 14)
    - Slonim (Chalidze), Vera, 1957-1973 (Box-folder 3: 15)
    - Slonim ( Phillimore), Maria, 1960-1974 (Box-folder 3: 16)
    - Stevens, O., 1976 (Box-folder 3: 17)
    - The Sunday Times, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 3: 18)
    - Thornhiill, Diana, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 19)
    - Waddington, Miriam, 1974 (Box-folder 3: 20)
    - Wettlin, Margaret Butterworth, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Speeches and writings, 1944-1981, undated.
    Includes annotations; literary reviews; and autobiographical, fictional, and other writings by Ivy Litvinov relating to her life in Great Britain and the Soviet Union. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Autobiographical notes, 1963-1973
      - Block notes, circa 1963, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 22)
        Includes notes from 1963 and 1973
      - Background material, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 3: 23-24, 4: 1-9, 5: 1-9)
        Includes holographs, typescripts, fragments, and notes.
    - Literary reviews, 1970-1981
      - Drafts, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 6: 1-2)
        Includes correspondence, 1973-1977.
      - Annotations to Leona Schechler manuscript American Families in Russia, circa 1970 (Box-folder 6: 3)
      - Engel, Barbara Alpern, Five Sisters: Women Against the Tsar, Alfred A. Knopf, New York, 1975 (Box-folder 6: 4)
      - Lawrence, D. H., The Boy in the Bush: The Forgotten Australian Novel, 1981 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - Stories, 1944-1975
      Includes drafts, fragments, notes, correspondence, and clippings.
      - "The Alihanyans,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 6: 6)
      - "Armenia,", 1957 (Box-folder 6: 7)
      - "The Barber's Story,", circa 1960 (Box-folder 6: 8)
      - "Being English in Moscow," autobiographical journal, 1973 (Box-folder 6: 9-10)
      - "Born in Wedlock,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 6: 11)
      - "The Boy Who Laughed," New Yorker, 1970 September 19 (Box-folder 6: 12)
      - "Cats in My Life,", 1975 (Box-folder 6: 13)
      - "The Collaborators,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 6: 14)
      - "Concert,", circa 1960 (Box-folder 6: 15)
      - "Dacha (At the Dacha),", 1963 (Box-folder 6: 16-18)
      - "Dream Houses,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 6: 19)
      - "Enid,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 6: 20)
      - "Everybody's Vulnerable,", 1957 (Box-folder 6: 21)
      - "Everyone Vulnerable,", 1944-1946 (Box-folder 7: 1-4)
        Notes, draft, typescript
      - "The Flat,", 1972 (Box-folder 7: 5)
      - "Funeral Home," poem, circa 1970 (Box-folder 7: 6)
      - "Game of Patience,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 7: 7)
      - "Gammer,", 1971 (Box-folder 7: 8)
      - "Greenacres,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 7: 9)
      - "Happiest Day,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 7: 10)
      - "Harrow,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 7: 11-12)
      - "I Met Katherine Mansfield,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 7: 13)
      - "If Two Are Not in Agreement, Can They Walk Together?,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 7: 14)
      - "In a Glass Darkly,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 7: 15)
      - "In Darkest England,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 8: 1)
      - "In Worlds Not Realized,", 1973 (Box-folder 8: 2)
      - "Inconstant Nymph,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 8: 3)
      - "Incoulation [sic] of Peter,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 8: 4)
      - "Jane Brown,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 8: 5)
      - "Ladies Only,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 8: 6-9)
      - "Lielupe Diary,", 1961 (Box-folder 8: 10)
      - "Little Masterpiece,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 8: 11)
      - "Litvinov's Wife,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 8: 12)
      - "Lonely Like Me,", circa 1975 (Box-folder 8: 13)
      - "Lucky Old Woman,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 8: 14)
      - "Maida Vale, 1904-1906,", circa 1963 (Box-folder 8: 15-16)
      - "Marriage at Its Worst,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 8: 17)
      - "Moscow,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - "Mrs. Chuck and Mrs. Doody,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 9: 2)
      - "My Visit to Erevan,", 1959 (Box-folder 9: 3)
        Includes notes, 1959.
      - "Of Reading and Writing,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 9: 4)
      - "The Point Reappearing,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 9: 5)
      - "Presentable,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 9: 6)
      - "Realms of Gold,", 1956 (Box-folder 9: 7)
      - "Revenant (Hilda Taylor),", circa 1970 (Box-folder 9: 8)
      - "Statesman at Home,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 9: 9-10)
      - "Thrush,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 9: 11)
      - "Twenty Years Ago,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 9: 12)
      - "Tynemouth,", 1973 (Box-folder 9: 13-15)
      - "Vernisazh,", 1956 (Box-folder 9: 16)
      - "Whose Daughter Art Thou?,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
      - "Widowhood,", circa 1975 (Box-folder 10: 3)
      - "Wistful, ", circa 1960 (Box-folder 10: 4)
      - "A Women of Feeling,", circa 1960 (Box-folder 10: 5-6)
    - Transcript of Ivy Litvinov's oral history interview, 1960 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Writings by others, 1988 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    Includes reviews of Ivy Litvinov's book She Knew She Was Right.
- Tatiana Litvinov File [part I], 1936-1997 (Boxes 10-18, 55)
  - Diaries, 1945-1997
    Tatiana Litvinov's diaries (numbered 1-57 by her) contain descriptions of life, politics, and social conditions in Great Britain and the Soviet Union. Each handwritten holograph includes a typewritten transcript.
    - Number 1 (pp. 1-29), 1945 June - July (Box-folder 10: 9)
    - Number 2 (pp. 30-60), 1942-1951 (Box-folder 10: 11-12)
    - Number 5 (pp. 271-323), 1953 September - December, undated (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Number 6 (pp. 324-377), 1953 June - August (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - Number 7 (pp. 378-397), 1950, 1951 (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - Number 8 (pp. 398-419), circa 1953 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Number 9 (pp. 420-439), 1953, 1954 (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Number 10 (pp. 440-452), 1954 June - July (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - Number 11 (pp. 453-477), 1954 February - March (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Number 12 (p. 478), 1954 August 4 (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - Number 13 (pp. 479-491), 1954 May (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - Number 14 (pp. 492-508), 1954 July - August (Box-folder 11: 10)
    - Number 15 (pp. 509-516), 1954 March, May, August (Box-folder 11: 11)
    - Number 16 (pp. 517-542), 1954, 1955 (Box-folder 11: 12)
    - Number 17 (pp. 543-552), 1955 January (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Number 18 (pp. 553-560), 1955 March - September (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - Number 19 (pp. 561-569), 1955 July (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - Number 20 (pp. 570-581), 1955, 1956 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - Number 21 (pp. 582-601), 1956 April - December (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - Number 22 (pp. 602-617), 1956, 1959 (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Number 23 (pp. 618-627), 1957 June - July (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - Number 24 (pp. 628-650), 1957 July - September (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - Number 25 (pp. 651-658), 1957 October (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Number 26 (pp. 659-681), 1958 March - April, 1959 July - August (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - Number 27 (pp. 682-820), 1958 (Box-folder 12: 11, 13: 1-2)
    - Number 28 (pp. 821-836), 1959 June - July (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - Number 29 (pp. 837-947), 1958, 1959 (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - Number 30, 1959-1970
      - pp. 61-155, 1959-1960, 1962-1965, 1970 (Box-folder 13: 5)
      - pp. 156-180, 1960 January - February (Box-folder 13: 6)
      - pp. 181-203, 1960 March - April (Box-folder 14: 1)
      - pp. 204-227, 1960 March - April (Box-folder 14: 2)
      - pp. 228-251, 1960 April - July (Box-folder 14: 3)
      - pp. 252-270, 1960 July - September (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Number 31 (pp. 956-991), 1960-1962, 1972 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Number 32 (pp. 992-1067), 1960-1962 (Box-folder 14: 6-7)
    - Number 33 (pp. 1068-1079), undated (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Number 34 (pp. 1080-1085), 1962 June, 1967 January (Box-folder 14: 9)
    - Number 35 (pp. 1086-1091), 1952 October - December (Box-folder 14: 10)
    - Number 36 (pp. 1092-1096), 1955 September - November (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - Number 37 (p. 1097), undated (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Number 38 (pp. 1098-1101), 1961-1974 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Number 39 (pp.1102-1119), 1962 September - October (Box-folder 15: 3-4)
      Includes English version.
    - Number 40 (pp. 1120-1129), 1963 January - February (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Number 41 (pp. 1130-1144), 1963 February - March (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - Number 42 (pp. 1145-1230), 1963 March - November, 1965 September - October (Box-folder 15: 7-8)
    - Number 43 (pp. 1231-1233), 1963 December 15 (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - Number 44 (pp. 1234-1241), 1963 (Box-folder 15: 10)
      General note
      See also: Diary number 53.
    - Number 45 (pp. 1242-1259), 1964 March - November (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - Number 46 (pp. 1260-1271), 1964 June - December, 1966 January (Box-folder 15: 12, 16: 1)
    - Number 47 (pp. 1272-1272a), 1964, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - Number 48 (pp. 1273-1974), 1965 (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - Number 49 (pp. 1275-1287), 1965 January - September (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - Number 50 (pp. 1288-1298), 1967 May - August (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - Number 51 (pp. 1299-1302), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - Number 52 (p. 1303), 1963 December 25 (Box-folder 16: 7)
    - Number 53 (pp. 1304-1313), 1967, 1969, 1973, 1975, 1997 (Box-folder 16: 8)
    - Number 54 (pp.1314-1325), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 16: 9)
    - Number 55 (pp. 1326-1340), 1969-1972, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 16: 10)
    - Number 56 (pp.1341-1342), 1969 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - Number 57 (pp. 1343-1361), 1973-1997 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1977
    Includes both personal and business correspondence. Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
    - Letters of condolence received by Tatiana Litvinov on the death of Ivy Litvinov, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 17: 3)
      Includes a photograph depicting Ivy Litvinov in Moscow in 1967 and "Certified Copy of an Entry: Pursuant to the Births and Death Registration Act 1953," 1981.
    - Carswell, Ianthe and John, 1966-1980 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - Grace, E., 1976 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - Litvinov, Ivy, 1936-1976
      - Undated (Box-folder 17: 6-8)
      - 1936 (Box-folder 17: 9)
      - 1937 (Box-folder 17: 10)
      - 1938 (Box-folder 17: 11)
      - 1939 (Box-folder 17: 12)
      - 1941 (Box-folder 17: 13)
      - 1942 (Box-folder 17: 14)
      - 1945-1947 (Box-folder 17: 15)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 17: 16)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 18: 1)
      - 1952 (Box-folder 18: 2)
      - 1954 (Box-folder 18: 3)
      - 1956 (Box-folder 18: 4)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 18: 5)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 18: 6)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 18: 7)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 18: 8)
      - 1962 (Box-folder 18: 9)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 18: 10)
      - 1964 (Box-folder 18: 11)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 18: 12)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 18: 13)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 18: 14)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 18: 15)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 18: 16)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 18: 17)
      - 1971 (Box-folder 18: 18)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 18: 19)
      - 1973 (Box-folder 18: 20)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 18: 21)
      - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 18: 22)
    - Litvinov, Maksim Maksimovich, 1941-1951
      - 1941 (Box-folder 18: 23)
      - 1942 (Box-folder 18: 24)
      - 1945 (Box-folder 18: 25)
      - 1946 (Box-folder 18: 26)
      - 1951 (Box-folder 18: 27)
    - Roberts, Judith, 1977 (Box-folder 18: 28)
  - Sound recordings and electronic documents, 1959-1960, undated
    - Five 3.5" floppy discs containing Tatiana Litvinov documents, undated (Box 55)
    - Five compact sound cassettes recordings of Tatiana Litvinov diaries, 1959-1960 (Box 55)
- Ivy Litvinov File [part II], 1941-1978 (Boxes 19-20)
  - Biographical file, 1974 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    Includes Ivy Litvinov's Soviet Union passport.
  - Correspondence, 1941-1978
    - Drafts, 1950-1973 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Unidentified, circa 1973 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - General, 1942-1977 (Box-folder 19: 4-5)
    - Bell, Adrian, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 19: 6-8)
    - Carswell, John, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - Chukovskii, Kornei, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 19: 10)
    - Curdy, Alison, 1976 (Box-folder 19: 11)
    - Dunn, Alan, 1971 (Box-folder 19: 12)
    - Freidin, Gregory, 1973 (Box-folder 19: 13)
    - Goldberg, Anatolii M., 1972-1974 (Box-folder 19: 14)
    - Grace, E., 1972 (Box-folder 19: 15)
    - Harari, M., 1963 (Box-folder 19: 16)
    - Horder, M., circa 1965 (Box-folder 19: 17)
    - Jones, E., circa 1970 (Box-folder 19: 18)
    - Kazakevich, E. L., 1960 (Box-folder 19: 19)
    - Kilbride, J, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 19: 20)
    - Kollontai, Aleksandra Mikhailovna, 1948 (Box-folder 19: 21)
    - Litvinov, Mikhail Maksimovich, 1941-1975 (Box-folder 19: 22)
    - Litvinov, Pavel Mikhailovich, 1960 (Box-folder 19: 23)
    - Litvinova, Nina, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 19: 24)
    - Litvinova (nee Iasinovskaia), Flora, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 19: 25)
    - Loos, Anita, circa 1970 (Box-folder 19: 26)
    - Low, Barbara, 1955 (Box-folder 19: 27)
    - Lyons, Leonard, 1975 (Box-folder 19: 28)
    - MacKenzie, Rachel, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 19: 29)
    - Maxwell, William, 1976 (Box-folder 19: 30)
    - McAuliffe, William C., 1973-1976 (Box-folder 19: 31)
    - Norman, Dorothy, 1973 (Box-folder 19: 32)
    - Proctor, T., 1971 (Box-folder 19: 33)
    - Rantz, Berta, 1976 (Box-folder 19: 34)
    - Skraly, Emile, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 19: 35)
    - Slonim (Chalidze), Vera, 1950-1974 (Box-folder 19: 36)
    - Slonim (Phillimore), Maria, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 19: 37)
    - Staige, William, 1971 (Box-folder 19: 38)
    - Urushadze, Venera, 1965 (Box-folder 19: 39)
    - Westlake, Alan, circa 1970 (Box-folder 19: 40)
    - Wettlin, Margaret Butterworth, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 19: 41)
    - Williams, Emlyn, 1957 (Box-folder 19: 42)
  - Notebook, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 1)
- Mikhail Maksimovich Litvinov File, 1924-1992 (Box 20)
  - Letters to parents, 1924-1943
    - 1924-1930 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - 1941 (Box-folder 20: 3-4)
    - 1942 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - 1943 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Materials relating to Mikhail Litvinov's hobby "Origami,", circa 1992 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    Includes handmade origami instructions book for children, photographs, and clippings.
- Tatiana Litvinov File [part II], 1890-2008 (Boxes 20-54)
  - Biographical file, 1976-2006 (Box-folder 20: 8)
    Includes Soviet and British passports, and certified copy of an entry of birth.
  - Correspondence, 1933-2008
    - Unidentified, 1982-2001 (Box-folder 20: 9)
    - General, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - Becker, John, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 20: 11)
    - Berlin, Isrial', 1981-1998 (Box-folder 20: 12)
    - Budulak-Sharygin, Nikolai, 1975 (Box-folder 20: 13)
      Includes letters to Mal'va Landa.
    - Bukovskii, Vladimir, 1979-2000 (Box-folder 20: 14)
    - Busfield (Buss), Brion, 1984-2007 (Box-folder 20: 15-16)
    - Campbell, J., 1999 (Box-folder 20: 17)
    - Chalidze, M., 1980 (Box-folder 20: 18)
    - Chalidze, Valerii, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 20: 19)
    - Cheever, Benjamin Hale, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 20: 20)
    - Cheever, John, 1965-1986
      Includes Tatiana Litvinov's draft letters to John Cheever.
      - 1965-1968 (Box-folder 21: 1)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 21: 2)
      - 1976 (Box-folder 21: 3)
      - 1980-1986 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - Chukovskaia (Chukovskaya), Elena, 1976-2008
      - 1976 (Box-folder 21: 5)
      - 1977 (Box-folder 21: 6)
      - 1978 (Box-folder 21: 7)
      - 1982-1985 (Box-folder 21: 8)
      - 1987-1988 (Box-folder 21: 9)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 21: 10)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 21: 11)
      - 1991 (Box-folder 21: 12)
      - 1992 (Box-folder 21: 13)
      - 1994-2008 (Box-folder 21: 14)
    - Chukovskaia (Chukovskaya), Lidiia (Lydia), 1989-1994 (Box-folder 21: 15)
    - Chukovskaia, Marina, circa 1975 (Box-folder 21: 16)
    - Chukovskii, Kornei Ivanovich, 1950-1968, undated
      - Undated (Box-folder 21: 17-18)
      - 1950-1951 (Box-folder 21: 19)
      - 1954-1955 (Box-folder 22: 1)
      - 1956-1958 (Box-folder 22: 2)
      - 1959-1960 (Box-folder 22: 3)
      - 1961-1962 (Box-folder 22: 4)
      - 1965-1966 (Box-folder 22: 5)
      - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Creffield, Dennis and Jullian, 1992-2007 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Danielson, Elena S., 1989 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Eikhenbaum, Boris Mikhailovich, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 22: 9-10)